pubnub.com 2012-09-15

# Privacy Policy

_Date of Last Revision: May 22, 2012_

  1. **Our Commitment to Protecting Your Privacy.** PubNub is committed to ensuring the privacy of your personal information entered while using the PubNub website, as well as the privacy of data that is processed by the PubNub Services. By visiting this site and using the PubNub Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

We may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to review updates that may occur.

  2. **PubNub Account Information.**
    1. PubNub Service Registration. When you sign up for the PubNub Services, we collect your email address, name and other contact information. We also collect your payment information as well as other information required to configure, use, pay for, and receive support for the PubNub Services. You can choose not to provide certain information, but this may impair your ability to use the PubNub Services. 
    2. Automatic Information. This site, like many other sites, records your IP address, time you visited, and may use cookies to track site usage and assist with website account session authentication and identification when you visit our site. 
    3. Usage of Information. The information we collect is used to administer our business activities, including but not limited to invoicing and customer support. Your email address will be used to notify you of critical updates, account information, and announcements. You can opt out of these emails if you like. 
    4. Sharing of Information. We do not share, sell, rent, or trade any information that you provide with third parties except as required to provide you the PubNub Services and as specified in this policy. 
    5. Third Party Service Providers. We may share information we collect with our third party service providers that assist with our provisioning of the PubNub Services. Third party service providers that we use are required to protect all data provided hereunder as PubNub confidential information, restricting disclosure to any other third party. 
    6. Credit Card Processing Provider. PubNub uses a third party credit card processing provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use billing information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf, and is subject to confidentiality obligations restricting the disclosure of information collected to other third parties. 
    7. Attribution. PubNub may include a list of customers of the PubNub Services as well as testimonials on the PubNub website that contains a customer name, logo and associated employee name and title. Customer consents to such listing or posting of testimonials 
    8. Public Forums. Any information you post on any PubNub provided blog, bulletin board or similar forum may be freely used by PubNub, any PubNub customer or any other visitor to such forum, and therefore, you shall have no expectation of privacy with any data included in such forum, and consent to such usage by any party mentioned herein, or any other third party. 
    9. Required by Law. PubNub reserves the right to use or disclose information provided if required by law or if we reasonably believe that use or disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process. 

  3. **Data Transacted through the PubNub Services.**
    1. Use of the PubNub Services requires that data be sent ("Published") and received ("Subscribed") through the PubNub Services. Data Published to and Subscribed from the PubNub Services may be used by PubNub to help with the development, tuning and scaling of the PubNub Services, including the generation of reports. Reporting is used both for internal use and to provide reports available to the PubNub customer associated with such provided data. PubNub will keep all data private, and will not share data with any third parties, except as an aggregate across multiple PubNub customers (for example, advertising the total number of messages sent through the PubNub Service per day). Occasionally we may use the information collected herein to notify you about new services or special offers. 
    2. PubNub provides various levels of security and encryption for data Published to the PubNub Services. Some levels of security and encryption may be offered to our customers at an additional cost. Please check the PubNub documentation for up-to-date information on the various security levels offered by the PubNub Services. 
    3. If you are a customer of a service that is powered by PubNub and have questions about privacy, please contact the provider of the service to inquire about their privacy policy. 

  4. **Children.** The PubNub website and PubNub Services are designed exclusively for adults. If you are under 18, you may only use the PubNub website and PubNub Services with the involvement of a parent or guardian. 

  5. **Consent.** By accessing and using the PubNub website and PubNub Services, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This is our entire and exclusive Privacy Policy and it supersedes any earlier version. Our Terms of Service take precedence over any conflicting Privacy Policy provision contained herein. We may change this Privacy Policy by posting a new version of this Privacy Policy on this website. It is your responsibility to review all updated versions of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review our Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the personally identifiable information we collect. Your continued use of the PubNub website or PubNub Services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates. 

  6. **Changes to Privacy Policy.** If our Privacy Policy or procedures change, we will immediately post those changes to our website. Any such changes will be effective immediately upon being posted, unless otherwise stated in the change. 

  7. **Contacting PubNub.** If you believe that PubNub has not adhered to this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at help@pubnub.com or by postal mail at PubNub Inc., 1045 17th Street #204, San Francisco, CA 94107 and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to remedy the problem.
